Guide to the Harry Altshuler Collection
University of Kansas
Harry Altshuler papers
1944-1994
University of Kansas Kenneth Spencer Research Library Department of Special Collections 1450 Poplar Lane, Lawrence, KS 66045-7616 Phone: (785)864-4334 Fax: (785)864-5803 URL: http://spencer.lib.ku.edu
Altshuler, Harry, 1913?-1990
3 linear feet (6 boxes)
Philadelphia, Pennsylvania native Harry Altshuler (c.1913-1990) was a journalist, literary agent, and author. This collection of his papers reflects his years as a literary agent, containing numerous tearsheets of stories sold by Altshuler as well as his business correspondence with authors and literary representatives.
MS 251
BIOGRAPHY of Harry Altshuler
Harry Altshuler was born circa 1913 in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. He was a was a journalist, literary agent, and author. Altshuler joined The Newark Star-Ledger in 1947. He moved to The New York Mirror as a rewrite man in 1955 and later was a feature writer for The World-Telegram and The Sun.
Altshuler published a novel in 1968 entitled She's Crazy, You'll Love Her under the pseudonym Joe Bruns.
As a literary agent, Altshuler worked with Robert Bloch, author of Psycho, the text that inspired Alfred Hitchcock's movie, and with other Science Fiction authors such as Roger Dee, Franklin Gregory, and Robert Sheckley.
Later in career, Altshuler worked for The National Enquirer and The Globe. He died in 1990.
SCOPE and CONTENTS
The Harry Altshuler papers range in date from 1944-1994 and contains professional correspondence and papers that reflect his career as a literary agent. Correspondence is the largest portion of the collection at 1.5 linear feet (3 boxes). The correspondence is generally between Altshuler and his clients, but is also between Altshuler and various publishers and reflect the interests of his clients. Among the correspondence are also Royalty Earning reports and publisher catalogs.
The tearsheets of stories sold by Altshuler are 1 linear foot (2 boxes) of the collection. These reflect approximately 114 stories that Altshuler sold to various magazines. The authors represented are Franklin Gregory, Roger Dee, Robert Sheckley, Alice Eleanor Jones, and Damon Knight.
Franklin Gregory's collection of short stories, Beyond the Blue Door, is contained in the smallest portion of the collection at .5 linear foot (1 box). This portion of the collection includes the table of contents for Beyond the Blue Door and correspondence about the book. There are also handwritten lists on manila envelopes with lists of submissions of various short stories and a list of authors.
INDEX TERMS
Names:
Altshuler, Harry,c.1913-1990; Asimov, Isaac, 1920-1990; Wollheim, Donald, 1914-1990; Gunn, Jim, 1923-; Dee, Roger, 1914-2004; Gregory, Franklin; Knight, Damon, 1922-2002; Bloch, Bob, 1917-1994; Sheckley, Robert, 1928-2005; Outlaw, Louise; Farnham, Alice Drayton; Rhoads, Gerda; Matheson, Richard, 1926-; McMillan, Dennis; McMillin, Guy; Jones, Alice Eleanor; Nourse, Alan E.; Sheldon, Walt, 1917-; Smith, Cordwainer, 1913-1966; Linebarger, Paul, 1913-1966; Dorémieux, Alain; Steger, Shelby
Organizations:
Frederic Brown Books; Dell books; Dell Publishing; Bantam Books; Ballantine Books; Avon Books; Warner Books; Candar Publishing; Quinn Publishing; New York Times Book Review; Reader's Digest; Good Housekeeping; Ladies Home Journal; McCall's; Redbook; New American Library; Silhouette Books; Harlequin Books; Harlequin Enterprises; Pyramid Communications; Pyramid Publications
Restrictions on Access
These materials are stored in the KU Annex off-site storage area.
All researchers interested in reviewing this material must consult Spencer Research Library staff (785-864-4334, 8-5 M-F CST) no less than three days in advance of a planned visit. Be advised that drop-in requests for this material can not be accommodated.
Acquisition Information
Jean Altshuler, 1994
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
  - Tearsheets of stories sold by Altshuler. (Box Box 1)
    - Farnham, Alice. "The Pie that Said Hello." Story Digest, vol. 1, no. 6, January 1947. (Folder 1)
    - Dee, Roger. "The Poundstone Paradox." FSF, vol. 6, no. 5, May 1954. (Folder 2)
    - Dee, Roger. "Man Friday." FSF,vol. 6, no. 3, March 1954. (Folder 3)
    - Dee, Roger. "Guest Artist." Fantastic, vol. 2, no. 3, May-June 1953. (Folder 4)
    - Dee, Roger. "The Frogs of Mars." Imagination, vol. 5, no. 4., April, 1954. (Folder 5)
    - Dee, Roger. "The Springbird," Beyond, vol. 1, no. 1, July 1953. (Folder 6)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "Pigs ain't Pigs," Adventure, vol. 116, no. 6, April 1947. (Folder 7)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "The Pocket of Wun Tu Foo," Adventure, vol. 115, no. 4, August 1946. (Folder 8)
    - Farnham, Alice Drayton. "Morne Perdu." Weird Tales, vol. 44, no. 3, March 1952. (Folder 9)
    - Farnham, Alice. "Black as the Night." Weird Tales, vol. 44, no. 7, November 1952. (Folder 10)
    - Farnham, Alice. "Lover, Come Back." Story, vol. XXV, no. 110, November-December 1944. (Folder 11)
    - Farnham, Alice. "The Song the Soldiers Sang." Story, vol. XXIV, no. 107, May-June 1944. (Folder 12-13)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "Operating Instructions," Astounding, vol. LI, no. 3, May 1953. (Folder 14)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "The PErfect Woman," [Amazing Stories, December 1953-January 1954]. (Folder 15)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "Conquerer's Planet," Fantastic Universe, vol 2, no. 3, October 1954. (Folder 16)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "Carrier." If, vol. 3, no. 2, April 1954. (Folder 17)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "What Goes Up." Science Fiction Adventures, vol, 1, no. 4, May 1953. (Folder 18)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "The PErfect Woman." [Amazing Stories, December 1953-January 1954]. (Folder 19)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "Diplomatic Immunity." [Galaxy, August 1953]. (Folder 20)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "The Hungry." Fantastic, June [1954]. (Folder 21)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "Keep Your Shape,." [Galaxy, November 1953]. (Folder 22)
    - O'Donnevan, Rinn [Robert Sheckley]. "Subsistence Level." Galaxy, vol. 8, no. 5, August 1954. (Folder 23)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "The Odour of Thought." New Worlds Science Fiction, vol. 9, no. 25, July 1954. (Folder 24)
    - Rhoads, Gerda. "My Past is Mine." [Fantastic Universe, October 1954]. (Folder 25)
    - Matheson, Richard. "Born of Man and Woman." FSF, vol. I, no. 3, Summer 1950. (Folder 26)
    - Smith, Evelyn E. "Floyd of the Eumenides." [Fantastic Universe, December 1955]. (Folder 27)
    - Wallace, F.L. "The Music Master." [Imagination, November 1953.] (Folder 28)
    - Matheson, Richard. "SRL Ad," FSF, vol. 3, no. 2, April 1952. (Folder 29)
    - Knight, Damon. "Turncoat." Thrilling Wonder Stories, vol. XLII, no. 1, April 1953. (Folder 30)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "The Monsters." [FSF, March 1953.] (Folder 31)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "The King's Wishes." [FSF, July 1953.] (Folder 32)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "The Street of the Damned." Doc Savage, vol. XXVIII, no. 1, September 1946. (Folder 33)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "The Seeing Eye." The Shadow, vol. L, no. 5, January 1946. (Folder 34)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "Earth Shaker." [Beyond, September 1954.] (Folder 35)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "The Big Sneeze." Doc Savage, vol. XXIX, no. 4, September-October 1947. (Folder 36)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "The Big Breeze." Beyond, vol. 1, no. 3, November 1953. (Folder 37)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "Stop on the Red." Fantastic, vol. 2, no. 2, March-April 1953. (Folder 38)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "The Wonderful Benny." Doc Savage, vol. XXX, no. 3, July-August 1948. (Folder 39)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "The Street of the Damned." Doc Savage, vol. XXVIII, no. 1, September 1946. (Folder 40)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "Specialist." Galaxy, [May 1953]. (Folder 41)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "Warm." Galaxy, [June 1953]. (Folder 42)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "Warrior Race." Galaxy, [November 1952]. (Folder 43)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "Potential." Astounding, [November 1953]. (Folder 44)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "Minority Group." Fantastic Universe, vol. 2, no. 4, November 1954. (Folder 45)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "Restricted Area." Amazing Stories, [June-July 1953]. (Folder 46)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "Specialist." Galaxy, [May 1953]. (Folder 47)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "What a Man Believes." Fantastic, vol. 2, no. 6, November-December 1953. (Folder 48)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "The Slow Season." FSF, vol. 7, no. 4, October 1954. (Folder 49)
    - O'Donnevan, Finn [Robert Sheckley]. "Uncle Tom's Planet." Galaxy, [December 1954]. (Folder 50)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "The Last Weapon." New Worlds Science Fiction, vol. 9, no. 26, August 1954. (Folder 51)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "Change from a Silver Dollar." The Saint, vol. 5, May 1954. (Folder 52)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "Off-Limits Planet," Imagination, vol. 5, no. 5, May 1954. (Folder 53)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "The Hour of Battle." Space Science Fiction, vol. 2, no. 2, September 1953. (Folder 54)
    - Knight, Damon. "Definition." Startling Stories, vol. 29, no. 1, February 1953. (Folder 55)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "Kilroy was Here." Adventure, vol. 116, no. 4, February 1947. (Folder 56)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "Pigs ain't Pigs." Adventure, vol. 116, no. 6, April 1947. (Folder 57)
  - Tearsheets of stories sold by Altshuler. (Box Box 2)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "The End of the World." Adventure, [October 1945]. (Folder 58)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "A Charge of Mayhem." Adventure, vol. 113, no. 4, August 1945. (Folder 59)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "Rugged Journey." Adventure, vol. 118, no. 3., January 1948. (Folder 60)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "A Charge of Mayhem." Adventure, vol. 113, no. 4, August 1945. (Folder 61)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "Cry Wolf, Cry Murder." Dime Mystery, vol. 35, no. 3, October 1947. (Folder 62)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "A Charge of Mayhem." Adventure, vol. 113, no. 4., August 1945. (Folder 63)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "The Devil to Pay." Adventure, vol. 116, no. 2, December 1946. (Folder 64)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "The End of the World." Adventure, vol. 113, no. 6, October 1945. (Folder 65)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "The Great Whaup." Dime Mystery, vol. 26, no. 3, February 1948. (Folder 66)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "Once in a Murderer's Moon." Dime Mystery, vol. 36, no. 1, December 1947. (Folder 67)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "The Poisonous Soul." 10-Story Fantasy, vol. 1, no. 1, Spring 1951. (Folder 68)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "The Screaming Shapes." Amazing Stories, [August 1950]. (Folder 69)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "Rugged Journey." Adventure, vol. 118, no. 3, January 1948. (Folder 70)
    - Gregory, Franklin. "The Pocket of Wun Tu Foo." Adventure, vol. 115, no. 4, August 1946. (Folder 71)
    - Jones, Alice Eleanor. "The Happy Clown." If, vol. 6, no. 1, December 1955. (Folder 72)
    - Jones, Alice Eleanor. "Life, Incorporated." Fantastic Universe, vol. 3, no. 3, April 1955. (Folder 73)
    - Dee, Roger. "The Enemy, Time." Space Stories, vol.2, no. 3, June 1953. (Folder 74)
    - Dee, Roger. "The Obligation." Startling Stories, vol. 27, no. 2, September 1952. (Folder 75)
    - Dee, Roger. "Oh Mesmerist from Mimas!" Planet Stories, vol. 5, no. 10, January 1953. (Folder 76)
    - Dee, Roger. "Palimpsest." Planet Stories, [vol.5, no. 3, November 1951]. (Folder 77)
    - Dee, Roger. "No Charge to the Membership." Startling Stories, vol. 28, no. 3, January 1953. (Folder 78)
    - Dee, Roger. "Legacy." Thrilling Wonder Stories, [Spring 1954]. (Folder 79)
    - Dee, Roger. "Holdup at Twin Palms." Black Book Detective, vol. XXIX, no. 3, Winter, Winter 1953. (Folder 80)
    - Starr, John [Roger Dee]. "Grim Green World." Planet Stories, vol. 5, no. 3, November 1951. (Folder 81)
    - Dee, Roger. "Girl from Callisto." Thrilling Wonder Stories, [June 1951]. (Folder 82)
    - Dee, Roger. "The Enemy, Time." Space Stories, vol. 2, no. 2, June 1953. (Folder 83)
    - Dee, Roger. "The Star Dice." Startling Stories, vol. 28, no. 1, November 1952. (Folder 84)
    - Dee, Roger. "Earthman's Choice." Science Fiction Adventures, vol. 1, no. 3, March 1953. (Folder 85)
    - Dee, Roger. "Clean Break." Galaxy, vol. 7, no. 2, November 1953. (Folder 86)
    - Jones, Alice Eleanor. "Miss Quatro." Fantastic Universe, vol. 3, no. 5, June 1955. (Folder 87)
    - Dee, Roger. "Today is Forever." Galaxy, September 1952. (Folder 88)
    - Dee, Roger. "The Persuasive Man." Science Fiction Adventures, vol. 1, no. 1, November 1952. (Folder 89)
    - Dee, Roger. "The Minister Had to Wait." Fantastic Universe, vol. 1, no. 1, June-July 1953. (Folder 90)
    - Dee, Roger. "Tiger's Cage."Science Stories, no. 4, April 1954. (Folder 91)
    - Dee, Roger. "The Poundstone Paradox." FSF, vol. 6, no. 5, May 1954. (Folder 92)
    - Dee, Roger. "The Anglers of Arz." If, vol. 1, no. 6, January 1953. (Folder 93)
    - Dee, Roger. "The Fresh Start." FSF,vol. 6, no. 1, January 1954. (Folder 94)
    - Dee, Roger. "The Interlopers." Astounding, [September 1954]. (Folder 95)
    - Dee, Roger. "Thank You, Member." Fantastic Universe, [December 1954]. (Folder 96)
    - Dee, Roger. "Pet Farm." Galaxy, vol. 7, no. 5-A, February 1954. (Folder 97)
    - Dee, Roger. "Clean Break." Galaxy, vol. 7, no. 2, November 1953. (Folder 98)
    - Dee, Roger. "The Man Who Found Out." Fantastic Universe, [September 1954]. (Folder 99)
    - Dee, Roger. "Problem on Balak." Galaxy, vol. 6, no. 6, September 1953. (Folder 100)
    - Dee, Roger. "To Remember Charlie By." Fantastic Universe, [March 1954]. (Folder 101)
    - Dee, Roger. "Wailing Wall." Galaxy, July 1952. (Folder 102)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "The Ogre Test."Planet Stories, vol. 6, no. 7, Summer 1954. (Folder 103)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "Hex on Hax." Planet Stories, [Fall 1954]. (Folder 104)
    - Sheckley, Robert. "Ultimatum!" Future Science Fiction, [November 1953]. (Folder 105)
    - Dee, Roger. "Assignment's End." Galaxy, [December 1954]. (Folder 106)
    - Dee, Roger. "The Dog that LIked Carmen." Orbit, [vol. 1, no. 3, May 1954]. (Folder 107)
    - Dee, Roger. "Have Tux-Will Travel." Infinity, vol. 1, no. 1, November 1955. (Folder 108)
    - Dee, Roger. "The Reasonable People." Thrilling Wonder Stories, vol. XLI, no. 1, October 1952. (Folder 109)
    - Dee, Roger. "Paradox Planet." Thrilling Wonder Stories, vol. XLI, no. 2, December 1952. (Folder 110)
    - Dee, Roger. "No Charge to the Membership."Startling Stories, vol. 28, no. 3, January 1953. (Folder 111)
    - Dee, Roger. "Dead Weight." [New Detective, June 1953] (Folder 112)
    - Dee, Roger. "No Charge to the Membership." Startling Stories, vol. 28, no. 3, January 1953. (Folder 113)
    - Eynon, David Lewis. "An Old, Old Friends." Fantastic Universe, [November 1954]. (Folder 114)
  - Correspondence., For a comprehensive list of items in this box, ksrl.sc.altshulerharry3.pdf (Box Box 3)
    - Various correspondents, 1989-1990; 19 Letters. (Folder 115)
      Outlaw, Louise Lee. "I'll Always Remember Harry," ts, ph, 1p
    - "Armchair Detective" - Correspondence, 1977; 1 letters (Folder 116)
    - Letter from Isaac Asimov to Harry Altshuler, June 4, 1980; 1 p + env (Folder 117)
    - Letters from Newton Baird, Talisman Press) to Harry Altshuler, 1986-1988; 16 letters. (Folder 118)
      Letter